so the iron law of performance can
easily be applied when we spend a
constant number of Cycles for each
instruction but how about unequal
instruction execution times meaning we
spend different numbers of Cycles for
different instructions so this is our
original iron law of performance the
number of instructions per program times
the number of cycles per instruction
times the clock cycle time if we have
different clock cycles per instruction
this part becomes a sum for all types of
instructions the instruction count of
that type that we have to execute times
the cycles per instruction for that type
of instruction note that in the original
iron love performance this was really
how many cycles we need to execute the
program this is how many cycles we need
for each type of instructions all of
them in a program and the sum here is
simply summing up over all types of
instructions so this is still the number
of Cycles we execute in a program and we
still have the clock cycle time here so
the new C few time here is like this so
if we have different CPI meaning
different cycles per instruction for
different types of instructions then we
need to do this and just multiply that
with the clock cycle time